Guide to Davis Hurd Collection
Erie Canal Museum
Davis Hurd Collection
1812 - 1869
Correspondence of Davis Hurd, Engineer and Surveyor. Hurd was the resident engineer in charge of the Erie Canal enlargement from Brockport, NY to Buffalo, NY.
2 boxes
Hurd, Davis, 1788-1868
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
Davis Hurd (1788-1868) was a surveyor and engineer. He was the resident engineer in charge of the enlargement of the Erie Canal between Brockport, NY and Buffalo, NY, and performed surveys for other canals around the country. He served as chief engineer for the Farmington Canal in Connecticut and Massachusetts. His brother, Jarvis Hurd, also worked as an engineer.
Erie Canal (N.Y.)
Personal correspondence of Davis Hurd to various family members and acquaintances. Many of the letters describe his work on the Erie Canal and surveying for other canals.
This collection was donated in 1977 by Wells E. Behee in memory of his grandmother, Fanny Judson Behee (1862-1948). Fanny was the granddaughter of Davis Hurd and inherited his papers.
- Correspondence
  - Corrspondence, 1813, 1812 - 1813
    - Correspondence, 1813, March, 1813; Includes item 77.109.2 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.2)
  - Correspondence, 1820-1829
    - Correspondence, 1820, Includes item 77.109.3 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.3)
    - Correspondence, 1821, Includes item 77.109.4 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.4)
    - Correspondence, 1822, Includes items 77.109.5, 77.109.6, 77.109.103 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.5, Folder 77.109.6, Box 2, Folder 77.109.103)
    - Correspondence, 1825, Includes items 77.109.7-.9, 77.109.104 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.7, Folder 77.109.8, Folder 77.109.9, Box 2, Folder 77.109.104)
    - Correspondence, 1826, Includes item 77.109.11 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.11)
    - Correspondence, 1829, Includes items 77.109.12-.20 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.12, Folder 77.109.13, Folder 77.109.14, Folder 77.109.15, Folder 77.109.16, Folder 77.109.17, Folder 77.109.18, Folder 77.109.19, Folder 77.109.20)
  - Correspondence, 1830-1839
    - Correspondence, 1830, Includes items 77.109.21-.22 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.21, Folder 77.109.22)
    - Correspondence, 1831, Includes item 77.109.105 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.105)
    - Correspondence, 1832, Includes items 77.109.23, 77.109.106 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.23, Box 2, Folder 77.109.106)
    - Correspondence, 1833, Includes item 77.109.24 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.24)
    - Correspondence, 1834, Includes item 77.109.107-.108 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.107, Folder 77.109.108)
    - Correspondence, 1835, Includes item 77.109.25 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.25)
    - Correspondence, 1836, Includes items 77.109.26-.28 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.26, Folder 77.109.27, Folder 77.109.28)
    - Correspondence, 1837, Includes items 77.109.29-.36 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.29, Folder 77.109.30, Folder 77.109.31, Folder 77.109.32, Folder 77.109.33, Folder 77.109.34, Folder 77.109.35, Folder 77.109.36)
    - Correspondence, 1838, 77.109.37-.38 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.37, Folder 77.109.38)
    - Correspondence, 1839, Includes items 77.109.39-.43 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.39, Folder 77.109.40, Folder 77.109.41, Folder 77.109.42, Folder 77.109.43)
  - Correspondence, 1840-1849
    - Correspondence, 1840, Includes items 77.109.44-.48 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.44, Folder 77.109.45, Folder 77.109.46, Folder 77.109.47, Folder 77.109.48)
    - Correspondence, 1841, Includes item 77.109.49 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.49)
    - Correspondence, 1842, Includes item 77.109.50 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.50)
    - Correspondence, 1844, Includes item 77.109.51 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.51)
    - Correspondence, 1845, Includes items 77.109.52-.57 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.52, Folder 77.109.53, Folder 77.109.54, Folder 77.109.55, Folder 77.109.56, Folder 77.109.57)
    - Correspondence, 1846, Includes items 77.109.58-.62 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.58, Folder 77.109.59, Folder 77.109.60, Box 2, Folder 77.109.61, Folder 77.109.62)
    - Correspondence, 1847, Includes item 77.109.63 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.63)
    - Correspondence, 1848, Includes items 77.109.64, 77.109.109 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.64, Folder 77.109.109)
    - Correspondence, 1849, Includes item 77.109.65 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.65)
  - Correspondence, 1850-1859
    - Correspondence, 1850, Includes items 77.109.66-.69 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.66, Folder 77.109.67, Folder 77.109.68, Folder 77.109.69)
    - Correspondence, 1851, Includes item 77.109.70 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.70)
    - Correspondence, 1852, Includes items 77.109.71-.73 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.71, Folder 77.109.72, Folder 77.109.73)
    - Correspondence, 1853, Includes items 77.109.74-.77 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.74, Folder 77.109.75, Folder 77.109.76, Folder 77.109.77)
    - Correspondence, 1854, Includes items 77.109.78-.79 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.78, Folder 77.109.79)
    - Correspondence, 1855, Includes item 77.109.80 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.80)
    - Correspondence, 1856, Includes items 77.109.81-.87 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.81, Folder 77.109.82, Folder 77.109.83, Folder 77.109.84, Folder 77.109.85, Folder 77.109.86, Folder 77.109.87)
    - Correspondence, 1857, Includes items 77.109.88-.92 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.88, Folder 77.109.89, Folder 77.109.90, Folder 77.109.91, Folder 77.109.92)
    - Correspondence, 1858, Includes items 77.109.93-.95 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.93, Folder 77.109.94, Folder 77.109.95)
  - Correspondence, 1860-1869
    - Correspondence, 1860, Includes item 77.109.96 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.96)
    - Correspondence, 1865, Includes item 77.109.97 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.97)
    - Correspondence, 1866, Includes item 77.109.98 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.98)
    - Correspondence, 1867, Includes item 77.109.99 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.99)
  - Correspondence, undated
    - Correspondence, undated, Includes items 77.109.10, 77.109.100-.101, 77.109.110 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.10, Box 2, Folder 77.109.100, Folder 77.109.101, Folder 77.109.110)
- Business Documents
  - Petitions
    - Petition, 1839, August 7, 1839; Handwritten petition from Fredonia citizens to Davis Hurd. Hurd has started a survey of the route for the contemplated canal from Buffalo to the state line and they ask him to consider a route through Chautaugua County by the Cassadaga Lake and outlet.; Includes item 77.109.102 (Box 2, Folder 77.109.102)
  - Invoices
    - Invoice, 1812, February 9, 1812; Includes item 77.109.1 (Box 1, Folder 77.109.1)